0. Tēnā koutou and Kia Ora and thank you for joining today on an adventure

1. Overlook

2. End Goal
   Our End Goal is to give the student a single central focus on their path from orienation, through graduation, and beyond.
   The view that allows pointed focus on each of the three important states on that path:
   I :  All the foundation they will lay down  - the "Required Courses"
   II:  All the foundation they have laid down - the "Complete Courses "
   III: The next things they can achieve - the "Possible Courses"

3. Inspiration
   Our Inspiration is three-fold
   I.   Though, to some, dated - Alvin Tofflers excellent Tome "Future Shock" which came out around the time I was born.
   II.  The Clear Desk Theory, which allows us to multi-task if we can hone our focus on the task relevant to the now.
   III. Eisenhower's Urgency-Importance Matrix, and the Have-To/Want-To Matrix which was inspire by it.

4. Design
   Our design, though platform agnostic, is implemented as an intersection between Visual Basic Net and Microsoft Access
   

5. Tool Set
   The three-part tool-set consists of Visual Basic Net, Microsoft Access, and the developers ability to understand multiple languages.

   Visual Basic was selected due to our developers long experience with Basic in general, and Visual Basic in particular.
   Furthermore, the IDE allows for rapid GUI prototyping using a drag-and-drop interface.
   Microsoft Access was chosen for its simpy installation configuration.
  
6. Investments And Returns
   The benefit of a database management system is its abilty to model a simplified read-world with relationships, states, and transitions.
   Also, the a database management system given an end-result - the what, and will worth the how for itself, return the results request.
   Second, it is easy, with a good relationship model, to model set-inclusion and set-exclusion.

7. The Back-End The Database Model
   The main relationsips modeled in this database design are:  <ERD: Full>
   The students   - the whom <ERD: Students>
   The courses    - the what <ERD: Courses>
   The Enrollment - the how  <ERD: Enrollment>
   
   And because this is a multi-user system in which the student can test alternate paths - the Enrollment is modeled are a path of steps and stops.
   And also, because their a rules that dictate what must be a foundation for what - these are represented by fields in the tables.

8. The Front-End GUI Interface
   The GUI is broken into three major panels
   The Student, The Enrollment, and The Courses
   <GUI: Student>
   <GUI: Enrollment>
   <GUI: Courses>

9. Work-Flow
   A Student moves through four major states
   A. Not Signed In
   B. Signing In 
   C. Signed In
   D. Signing Out	
   E. Signed Out


10. Future Extensions

Quantitative frequency of class offerings: Years, Seasons, Days and Times
Quantitative course load: pages to be read, pages to be written, work inside and outside of class, tests and their lengths.
Qualitative Student Input of familiarity and interest with the course topic

11. Feed Back Loop
    Tahu.Marinus@Gmail.Com


12. Resources
    	Books
     	SQL For Mere Mortals  - Viescas And Hernandez 
     	Future Shock          - Toffler
        Visual Basic Net 2003 - Halvorson